[thrilling music]
[car engine revving]
[engine stops]
[thrilling music]
[hisses]
[hissing]
[all hissing]
[panting]
[clattering]
[light music]
♪ Are you blind when you're born? ♪
♪ Can you see in the dark? ♪
♪ Can you look at a king? ♪
♪ Would you sit on his throne? ♪
♪ Can you say of your bite
That it's worse than your bark? ♪
♪ Are you cock of the walk
When you're walking alone? ♪
-♪ When you fall on your head ♪
-[whimpers]
♪ Do you land on your feet? ♪
[sniffs]
♪ Are you tense when you sense
There's a storm in the air? ♪
♪ Can you find your way blind
When you're lost in the street? ♪
♪ Do you know how to go
To the Heaviside Layer? ♪
♪ Because Jellicles can and Jellicles do ♪
♪ Jellicles do and Jellicles can ♪
♪ Jellicles can and Jellicles do ♪
♪ Can you ride on a broomstick
To places far distant? ♪
♪ Familiar with candle ♪
-♪ With book ♪
-♪ And with bell? ♪
♪ Were you Whittington's friend? ♪
♪ The Pied Piper's assistant? ♪
♪ Have you been an alumnus
Of heaven or hell? ♪
♪ Are you mean like a minx? ♪
♪ Are you lean like a lynx? ♪
♪ Are you keen to be seen ♪
♪ When you're smelling a rat? ♪
♪ Were you there when the pharaohs
Commissioned the Sphinx? ♪
♪ If you were and you are
You're a Jellicle cat ♪
♪ Jellicle songs for Jellicle cats
Jellicle songs for Jellicle cats ♪
♪ Jellicle songs for Jellicle cats ♪
♪ We can dive through the air ♪
♪ Like a flying trapeze ♪
♪ We can turn double somersaults
Bounce on a tire ♪
♪ We can run up a wall
We can swing through the trees ♪
♪ We can balance on bars
We can walk on a wire ♪
♪ Jellicles can and Jellicles do
Jellicles can and Jellicles do ♪
♪ Jellicle songs for Jellicle cats
Jellicle songs for Jellicle cats ♪
♪ Can you sing at the same time
In more than one key? ♪
♪ Duets by Rossini ♪
♪ And waltzes by Strauss ♪
♪ Ah-ah-ah, ah-ah ♪
♪ And can you, as cats do
Begin with a "C" ♪
[high-pitched singing]
♪ That always triumphantly
Brings down the house? ♪
♪ Jellicle cats are queens of the night ♪
♪ Singing at astronomical heights ♪
♪ Handling pieces from the Messiah ♪
♪ Hallelujah, angelical choir ♪
[warbling]
♪ The mystical divinity ♪
♪ Of unashamed felinity ♪
♪ Round the cathedral ♪
♪ Rang "Vivat" ♪
♪ Life to the Everlasting ♪
♪ Cat! ♪
♪ Feline, fearless, faithful and true ♪
♪ To others who do ♪
♪ What ♪
♪ Jellicles do and Jellicles can ♪
♪ Jellicles can and Jellicles do ♪
♪ Jellicle cats sing Jellicle chants ♪
♪ Jellicles old and Jellicles new ♪
♪ Jellicle song and Jellicle dance ♪
♪ Jellicle songs for Jellicle cats
Jellicle songs for Jellicle cats ♪
♪ Practical cats ♪
♪ Dramatical cats ♪
♪ Pragmatical cats ♪
♪ Fanatical cats ♪
♪ Oratorical cats ♪
♪ Delphicoracle cats ♪
♪ Skeptical cats ♪
♪ Dyspeptical cats ♪
♪ Romantical cats ♪
♪ Pedantical cats ♪
♪ Critical cats ♪
♪ Parasitical cats ♪
♪ Allegorical cats, metaphorical cats ♪
-♪ Statistical cats ♪
-♪ And mystical cats ♪
♪ Political cats ♪
♪ Hypocritical cats ♪
-♪ Clerical cats ♪
-♪ Hysterical cats! ♪
♪ Cynical cats ♪
♪ Rabbinical cats ♪
♪ And magical cats! ♪
♪ Jellicle songs for Jellicle cats
Jellicle songs for Jellicle cats ♪
♪ Jellicle songs for Jellicle cats... ♪
[gasps]
[Macavity] Going to the ball?
I wouldn't if I were you.
Could get dangerous.
You know, they say Macavity
will win this year.
Macavity?
♪ There's no one like Macavity ♪
A wonderful magician.
♪ But a monster of depravity ♪
One moment you see him...
Come on!
[Macavity] Magic!
-[Macavity laughing]
-[gasps]
So, what's your name?
[hissing]
Cat got your tongue?
-Victoria.
-Victoria?
You must have another.
Another?
The naming of cats is a difficult matter.
It isn't just one of your holiday games.
You may think at first
I'm as mad as a hatter
when I tell you a cat must have
three different names.
First of all, there's the name
that the family use daily.
-Such as...
-Peter.
-Augustus.
-Alonzo.
Or James.
But I tell you, a cat
needs a name that's particular.
A name that's peculiar and more dignified.
Else how can he keep up
his tail perpendicular,
or spread out his whiskers
or cherish his pride?
But above and beyond,
there's still one name left over.
And that is the name
that you never will guess.
The name that no human research
can discover.
But the cat herself knows
and will never confess.
When you notice a cat
in profound meditation,
the reason, I tell you as always the same.
Her mind is engaged
in a rapt contemplation
of the thought,
of the thought
of her name.
Her ineffable,
effable,
effanineffable,
deep, and inscrutable,
singular name,
name, name, name...
[light music]
[light music continues]
Mr. Mistoffelees, the magical cat!
♪ Jellicle cats come out tonight ♪
♪ Jellicle cats, come one, come all ♪
♪ The Jellicle moon is shining bright ♪
♪ Jellicles come to the Jellicle Ball ♪
♪ Jellicle cats come out tonight ♪
Je...
[yells]
♪ Jellicles come to the... ♪
[groans]
♪ Jellicle Ball ♪
♪ Jellicle cats meet once a year ♪
♪ At the Jellicle Ball
Where we all rejoice ♪
♪ And the Jellicle leader
Will soon appear ♪
♪ And make what is known
As the Jellicle choice ♪
♪ When Old Deuteronomy just before dawn ♪
♪ Through a silence
You feel you could cut with a knife ♪
♪ Announces the cat
Who can now be reborn ♪
♪ And come back
To a different Jellicle life ♪
♪ For waiting up there
Is the Heaviside Layer ♪
Full of wonders
one Jellicle only will see.
And Jellicles ask because Jellicles dare.
Who will it be?
[Jellicles] Who will it be?
The Heaviside Layer?
Far, far up in the sky.
From where the most deserving cat
will be reborn into another life.
So they can be
who they've always dreamed of being.
How will they be chosen?
By singing the song of themselves,
of course.
Who they are and what they do.
[dramatic music]
Come.
Come and see a cat who's competing
to be the Jellicle choice tonight.
♪ I have a Gumbie Cat in mind ♪
-♪ Her name is Jennyanydots ♪
-[yawns]
♪ Her coat is of the tabby kind ♪
♪ With tiger stripes and leopard spots ♪
♪ All day she sits upon the stair ♪
-♪ Or on the step or on the mat ♪
-[grunting]
♪ She sits and sits and sits and sits ♪
♪ And that's what makes a Gumbie Cat ♪
♪ That's what makes a Gumbie Cat ♪
[grunting]
♪ But... ♪
♪ When the day's hustle
And bustle is done ♪
♪ Then the Gumbie Cat's work
Is but hardly begun ♪
♪ And when all the family's
In bed and asleep ♪
♪ I tuck up my skirts
To the basement to creep ♪
♪ I am deeply concerned
With the ways of the mice ♪
♪ Their behavior's not good
And their manners not nice ♪
♪ So when I have got them
Lined up on the matting ♪
♪ I teach them music
Crocheting and tatting ♪
♪ Diddly-dot, diddly-dot
Diddly-dot, whap-whoo ♪
[scatting]
-♪ Woodly-wah, woodly-wah ♪
-It's dinner and a show.
♪ Woodly-wah, woodly-wah
Woodly-wah, wah-wah ♪
♪ A-dooby-dooby-doo
A-diddly-diddly-diddly-diddly ♪
[scatting]
[panting]
-[trap snaps]
-Aah!
[mice giggling]
[Munkustrap]
♪ I have a Gumbie Cat in mind ♪
♪ Her name is Jennyanydots ♪
♪ The curtain cord she likes to wind ♪
-♪ And tie it into sailor knots ♪
-[groaning]
♪ She sits upon the windowsill ♪
♪ Or anything that's smooth and flat ♪
♪ She sits and sits and sits and sits ♪
[groans]
♪ And that's what makes a Gumbie Cat! ♪
♪ That's what makes a Gumbie Cat! ♪
[clangs]
♪ But... ♪
♪ When the day's hustle
And bustle is done ♪
♪ Then the Gumbie Cat's work
Is but hardly begun ♪
♪ I think that the cockroaches
Need employment ♪
♪ To prevent them from idle
And wanton destroyment ♪
♪ So I formed from that lot
Of disorderly louts ♪
♪ A troop of well-disciplined
Helpful boy scouts ♪
♪ With a purpose in life
And a good deed to do ♪
♪ And I've even created ♪
♪ A Beetles' Tattoo! ♪
[rhythmic drumbeat]
[Jennyanydots] Cockroaches!
Faces!
Mmm.
And now for the icing on the cake.
Why does she want another Jellicle life?
I cannot keep being in this kitchen.
Don't get cocky!
[Jennyanydots] Ha-ha!
[lively music]
♪ So for Old Gumbie Cats
Let's now give three cheers ♪
♪ On whom well-ordered households depend
It appears ♪
♪ Three cheers, three cheers
Three cheers ♪
♪ Thank you, my dears ♪
[Rum Tum Tugger] Hmm. Meow.
[Jennyanydots] Hmm?
It's a little old-fashioned,
don't you think?
With the cockroaches dancing
and the mice singing.
Well, actually, the mice were really good.
[giggling]
But it's all a bit old-school.
Get out.
[Rum Tum Tugger] I'm just trying
to offer you some feedback here.
Well... Well, actually,
I just thought
I'd have a feed at the back.
Get out of this kitchen now.
Let's dance!
[upbeat music]
-♪ The Rum Tum Tugger is a curious cat ♪
-♪ A curious cat ♪
[both grunting rhythmically]
Hmm. Hmm.
♪ If you offer me pheasant
I'd rather have grouse ♪
♪ If you put me in a house
I would much prefer a flat ♪
♪ If you put me in a flat
Then I'd rather have a house ♪
-♪ If you set me on a mouse ♪
-[shrieking]
-♪ Then I only want a rat ♪
-[Jennyanydots] Aah! No, no!
♪ If you set me on a rat
Then I'd rather chase a mouse ♪
Thanks, Tugger!
[Jellicles]
♪ The Rum Tum Tugger is a curious cat ♪
♪ And there isn't any call
For me to shout it ♪
[Jellicles] ♪ For he will do as he do do ♪
♪ And there's no doing anything about it ♪
No!
♪ The Rum Tum Tugger is a terrible bore ♪
♪ When you let me in then I wanna go out ♪
♪ I'm always on the wrong side
Of every door ♪
♪ As soon as I get home
Then I like to get about ♪
♪ I like to lie in a bureau drawer ♪
♪ But I make such a fuss
If I can't get out ♪
-Ooh!
-Do you think he just got neutered?
'Cause those notes are, like...
[high-pitched voice]
...high.
-[chuckling]
-You know...
♪ The Rum Tum Tugger is a curious cat ♪
[grunts]
♪ And there isn't any use
For you to doubt it ♪
-Lights.
-♪ For he will do as he do do ♪
♪ And there's no doing anything
About-awow-awow it ♪
I can dance how he dances, too.
-Look.
-[Munkustrap] Let me see.
[hip-hop music]
It's easy.
♪ The Rum Tum Tugger is a curious beast ♪
♪ My disobliging ways
Is a matter of habit ♪
♪ If you offer me fish
Then I always want a feast ♪
♪ When there isn't any fish
Well, darling, I'm not having a rabbit ♪
♪ If you offer me cream
Then I sniff and sneer ♪
♪ For I only like... ♪
♪ What I find ♪
♪ For myself ♪
Uh!
-♪ Victoria ♪
-[Jellicles sighing]
Stop milking it.
♪ So you'll catch me in it
Right up to my ears ♪
♪ If you put it away on the larder shelf ♪
Whoo!
♪ The Rum Tum Tugger ♪
♪ Is artful and knowing ♪
♪ Doesn't care for a cuddle ♪
♪ But I'll leap up in your lap
In the middle of your sewing ♪
♪ For there's nothing I enjoy
Like a horrible muddle ♪
Yeah!
[bell dinging]
♪ The Rum Tum Tugger is a curious cat ♪
♪ The Rum Tum Tugger
Doesn't care for a cuddle ♪
Nah, nah. No more milk.
Milk!
Whoo!
♪ The Rum Tum Tugger is a curious cat ♪
♪ And there isn't any need
For me to spout it ♪
♪ For he will do as he do do ♪
♪ And there's no ♪
♪ Doing anything ♪
♪ About ♪
Wow.
♪ There's no doing anything, yeah ♪
♪ About ♪
[meowing]
♪ About it ♪
[whines]
[laughing]
[hissing]
[foreboding music]
[foreboding music continues]
♪ Remark the cat ♪
♪ Who hesitates towards you ♪
♪ In the light of the door ♪
♪ Which opens on her ♪
♪ Like a grin ♪
♪ You see the border of her coat ♪
♪ Is torn and stained with sand ♪
♪ And you see ♪
♪ The corner of her eye ♪
♪ Twist like a crooked pin ♪
♪ And-- ♪
♪ She haunted many a low resort ♪
♪ Near the grimy road of Tottenham Court ♪
♪ She flitted about the no-man's land ♪
♪ From the Rising Sun
To the Friend At Hand ♪
♪ And the postman sighed
As he scratched his head ♪
♪ You'd really have thought
She'd ought to be dead ♪
♪ And who'd have ever supposed that that ♪
♪ Was Grizabella ♪
♪ The glamor cat ♪
♪ Grizabella the glamor cat ♪
♪ Who'd have ever ♪
♪ Supposed that that ♪
[hisses]
♪ Was Grizabella ♪
♪ The glamor cat ♪
[breathing shakily]
[Victoria] Who was she?
She used to be the star of the Windmill.
Then she went with Macavity.
[Cassandra] Now, she lives
on the wasteland.
[heavy footsteps]
[tense music]
[Bustopher] Good evening, all.
Meow!
Oh, no. Look what the cat dragged in.
Oh, my. You look absolutely starving.
You can't attend the ball
on an empty stomach.
So, you're hoping to be chosen?
Yeah. He wants to be reborn as a thin cat,
so he can get fat all over again,
but he's going to lose!
How dare you! Don't listen to her.
Don't you listen to him
because he is a complete and utter--
♪ I'm Bustopher Jones
I'm not skin and bones ♪
♪ In fact, I'm remarkably fat ♪
♪ I don't haunt pubs
I have eight or nine clubs ♪
♪ For I'm the St. James's Street cat ♪
♪ I'm the cat they all greet
As I walk down the street ♪
♪ In my coat of fastidious black ♪
♪ No commonplace mousers
Have such well-cut trousers ♪
♪ Or such an impeccable back ♪
Yeah, you've got it. Here we go.
Ha-ha!
Ready?
Whoo!
[Macavity] 'Scuse me.
Are you, by any chance, Jennyanydots?
[chuckles]
Yes.
You know, your work should be
on the world stage.
Yes.
And that face should be on a poster.
[suspenseful music]
Meow!
♪ In the whole of St. James's
The smartest of names is ♪
-♪ The name of this Brummell of cats ♪
-[sipping]
♪ And we're all of us proud
To be nodded or bowed to ♪
♪ By Bustopher Jones in white spats ♪
[sighs]
♪ My visits are occasional
To the Senior Educational ♪
♪ And it is against the rules ♪
♪ For any one cat to belong both to that ♪
♪ And the Joint Superior Schools ♪
[inhales deeply]
[clattering]
♪ For a similar reason
When game is in season ♪
♪ I'm found not at Fox's but Blimp's ♪
Oh!
♪ I am frequently seen
At the gay Stage and Screen ♪
♪ Which is famous
For winkles and shrimps ♪
♪ In the season of venison
I give my ben'son ♪
♪ To the Pothunter's succulent bones ♪
♪ And just before noon's
Not a moment too soon ♪
[music stops]
Right. That's not going to work,
is it? Okay?
Look at you, and look at me, and you know,
you know that I'm sensitive
about my size, okay?
And yet you embarrass me. You...
[hisses]
That's what I say to you.
Okay? Now, listen.
You'll never get me up there on your own.
So let's gather up
a few more of the... cats,
and we'll try again, shall we?
Yeah. Okay. Nice and good.
Everybody ready? And... Five, six, seven.
♪ And just before noon's
Not a moment too soon... ♪
Hey! Ooh!
Gah!
Oh!
♪ To drop in for a drink at the Dro... ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, ...ones ♪
Thanks, Tugger.
♪ When I'm seen in a hurry
There's probably curry ♪
♪ At the Siamese or at the Glutton ♪
Ooh!
♪ If I look full of gloom
Then I've lunched at the Tomb ♪
♪ On cabbage, rice pudding, and mutton ♪
♪ In the whole of St. James's
The smartest of names is ♪
♪ The name of this Brummell of cats ♪
♪ And we're all of us proud
To be nodded or bowed to ♪
♪ By Bustopher Jones in white ♪
♪ Bustopher Jones in white ♪
♪ Bustopher Jones in white spats ♪
Yah!
Ha-ha! Hoo-hoo!
[laughing]
♪ So, much in this way
Passes Bustopher's day ♪
-♪ At one club ♪
-♪ Or another I'm found ♪
♪ It can be no surprise
That under our eyes ♪
♪ He has grown unmistakably round ♪
♪ I'm a 25-pounder or I am a bounder ♪
♪ And I'm putting on weight every day ♪
♪ But I'm so well preserved
Because I've observed ♪
♪ All my life a routine and I'd say ♪
♪ I am still in my prime
I shall last out my time ♪
♪ That's the word
From the stoutest of cats ♪
♪ It must and it shall
Be spring in Pall Mall ♪
♪ While Bustopher Jones wears white ♪
♪ Bustopher Jones wears white ♪
Spats?
Macavity!
[chuckles]
Puss in Spats.
I love it.
[gasping]
Hungry?
Look like you haven't eaten for days.
Go for it.
[Macavity] Look at it. Smell it.
-Really tasty.
-[sniffing]
Well, come on, Puss in Spats.
You can do it.
Ha-ha!
Ineffable.
[grunts]
Can we help you?
You really shouldn't be out alone.
I'm not alone. I'm with my friends.
-Friends?
-[gasps]
[Mungojerrie] Looks like they've run away
and left you.
[Rumpleteazer] Don't worry.
We'll look after you. Won't we?
Why don't you come inside?
♪ Mungojerrie ♪
♪ And Rumpleteazer ♪
♪ We're a notorious couple of cats ♪
♪ As knockabout clowns ♪
♪ Quick-change comedians ♪
♪ Tightrope walkers ♪
♪ And acrobats ♪
♪ We have an extensive reputation ♪
♪ We make our home in Victoria Grove ♪
♪ This is merely our center of operation ♪
♪ For we are incurably given to rove ♪
♪ We are very well known
In Cornwall Gardens ♪
♪ In Launceston Place
And in Kensington Square ♪
♪ We have really
A little more reputation ♪
♪ Than a couple of cats
Can very well bear ♪
No photos, right?
♪ If the area window is found ajar ♪
♪ And the bedroom looks
Like a field of war ♪
♪ If a tile or two comes loose
On the roof ♪
♪ Which presently fails to be waterproof ♪
[tiles clattering]
♪ If the drawers are pulled out
From the bedroom chest ♪
♪ And you can't find
One of your winter vests ♪
♪ Or after supper one of the girls ♪
♪ Suddenly misses her Woolworth pearls ♪
♪ The family will say ♪
♪ "It's that horrible cat" ♪
♪ It was Mungojerrie ♪
♪ Or Rumpleteazer ♪
♪ And most of the time
They leave it at that ♪
[laughing]
[giggles]
♪ Mungojerrie and Rumpleteazer
Have a very unusual gift of the gab ♪
♪ We're highly efficient
Cat burglars as well ♪
♪ And remarkably smart
At the smash-and-grab ♪
♪ We make our home in Victoria Grove ♪
♪ We have no regular occupation ♪
♪ We are plausible fellows
Who like to engage ♪
♪ A friendly policeman in conversation ♪
Hello, police officer.
I bought these for her myself.
-You did what?
-Wait.
♪ When the family assembles
For Sunday dinner ♪
♪ Their minds made up
That they won't get thinner ♪
♪ On Argentine joint potatoes and greens ♪
♪ Then the cook would appear
From behind the scenes ♪
♪ And say, in a voice
That is broken with sorrow ♪
♪ "I'm afraid you must wait
And have dinner tomorrow ♪
♪ For the joint
Has gone from the oven like that!" ♪
♪ Then the family will say ♪
♪ "It's that horrible cat" ♪
♪ It was Mungojerrie ♪
♪ Or Rumpleteazer ♪
♪ And most of the time
They leave it at that ♪
♪ Mungojerrie ♪
♪ And Rumpleteazer ♪
♪ Have a wonderful way
Of working together ♪
♪ And some of the time
You would say it was luck ♪
You would say it was weather ♪
♪ We go through the house
Like a hurricane ♪
♪ And no sober person
Could take his oath ♪
♪ Was it Mungojerrie? ♪
♪ Or Rumpleteazer? ♪
♪ Or could you have sworn
That it might have been both? ♪
♪ And when you hear a dining-room smash ♪
♪ Or up from the pantry
There comes a loud crash ♪
♪ Or down from the library
There comes a loud ping ♪
♪ From a vase
That was commonly said to be Ming ♪
♪ Then the family will say ♪
[Victoria] ♪ "Now, which was which cat?" ♪
♪ It was Mungojerrie ♪
♪ And ♪
♪ Rumpleteazer ♪
♪ And there's nothing at all
To be done about that ♪
[music stops]
[rumbling]
[shatters]
[dog barking]
[grunting]
[Mistoffelees] I'm coming, Victoria!
[groans]
Don't worry! Stay there!
[dog barking louder]
[dog growling]
[grunting]
[gasps]
Here, doggy! Fetch!
[both panting]
I've been looking for you everywhere.
Uh, I thought you'd miss the arrival.
What arrival?
Of Old Deuteronomy.
[dog growling]
Oh!
[gasps]
Where am I?
[ship horn blows]
[Jennyanydots] It seems we're on a barge
in the middle of the Thames.
[Bustopher] What are you doing here?
[Jennyanydots sighs]
I haven't got the faintest clue.
And I've lost all of my cockroaches.
I can't be on a barge
in the middle of the Thames.
I'm supposed to be going to the ball.
Oh, no.
You're not going anywhere, Puss in Spats.
I'm determined to win,
and I prefer my competition chained up.
Growltiger. Keep 'em here.
Meow!
He's called me that twice now.
"Puss in Spats."
Like it's sort of a joke.
I rather like it.
So the joke's on him.
Who are you?
Growltiger.
♪ I'm a Bravo Cat, I travel on a barge ♪
♪ In fact, I am the roughest cat
Whoever roamed at large ♪
♪ From Gravesend up to Oxford
I pursue my evil aims ♪
♪ Rejoicing in my title
of "The Terror of the Thames" ♪
Right, no, see, that doesn't rhyme.
You can't just say "Taymes"
'cause it rhymes with "aims."
It's the River Thames.
-[snarls]
-[whimpers]
[Griddlebone giggles]
Ow! Okay, so, it's Growltiger, you say?
Yep. I think I've got it.
I think that's it.
I fully understand now who it is.
Thank you for telling me.
[dramatic music]
Where have you been?
Oh, it's mine.
Yet another trick that went wrong.
[chuckles]
You're just in time
to see Old Deuteronomy.
Who is Old Deuteronomy?
♪ Old Deuteronomy's lived a long time ♪
♪ She's a cat who has lived
Many lives in succession ♪
♪ She was famous in proverb
And famous in rhyme ♪
♪ A long while before
Queen Victoria's accession ♪
♪ Old Deuteronomy's lived many lives ♪
♪ You know, I am tempted to say 99♪
♪ And her numerous progeny
Prospers and thrives ♪
♪ And the village is proud of her
In her decline ♪
♪ At the sight of that placid
And bland physiognomy ♪
♪ When she sits in the sun ♪
♪ On the vicarage wall ♪
♪ The oldest inhabitant croaks ♪
♪ "Well, of all things ♪
♪ Can it be really? ♪
♪ Yes, no, ho, hi, oh, my eye! ♪
♪ My mind may be wandering but I confess ♪
♪ I believe it is Old Deuteronomy!" ♪
♪ Well, of all things, can it be really? ♪
♪ Yes, no, ho, hi, oh, my eye! ♪
♪ My mind may be wandering but I confess ♪
♪ I believe it is Old Deuteronomy! ♪
♪ Well, of all things, can it be really? ♪
♪ Yes, no, ho, hi, oh, my eye! ♪
♪ My mind may be wandering but I confess ♪
♪ I believe it is Old Deuteronomy! ♪
♪ Well, of all things, can it be really? ♪
♪ Yes, no, ho, hi, oh, my eye! ♪
♪ My legs may be tottery, I must go slow ♪
♪ And be careful of Old Deuteronomy ♪
♪ Jellicle cats meet once a year ♪
♪ On the night
We make the Jellicle choice ♪
♪ And now the Jellicle leader is here ♪
♪ Jellicle cats can all rejoice! ♪
-Who will it be?
Who will it be?
[dramatic music]
♪ Jellicle cats come out tonight ♪
♪ Jellicle cats, come one, come all ♪
♪ The Jellicle moon is shining bright ♪
♪ Jellicles come to the Jellicle Ball ♪
[Jellicles]
♪ Jellicle cats are black and white ♪
♪ Jellicle cats are rather small ♪
♪ Jellicle cats are merry and bright ♪
♪ And pleasant to hear
When they caterwaul ♪
-[yowls]
-♪ Jellicle cats have cheerful faces ♪
♪ Jellicle cats have bright, black eyes ♪
♪ We like to practice
Our airs and graces ♪
♪ And wait for the Jellicle moon to rise ♪
-♪ Jellicle cats develop slowly ♪
-Meow, meow, meow, meow!
♪ Jellicle cats are not too big ♪
♪ Jellicle cats are roly-poly ♪
♪ We know how to dance
A gavotte and a jig ♪
♪ Until the Jellicle moon appears ♪
♪ We make our toilette
And take our repose ♪
♪ Jellicles wash behind their ears ♪
♪ Jellicles dry between their toes ♪
♪ Jellicle cats are white and black ♪
♪ Jellicle cats are of moderate size ♪
♪ Jellicles jump like a jumping jack ♪
♪ Jellicle cats have moonlit eyes ♪
♪ Jellicle cats are black and white ♪
♪ Jellicle cats, as we said, are small ♪
♪ If it happens to be a stormy night ♪
♪ We will practice
A caper or two in the hall ♪
♪ If it happens the sun
Is shining bright ♪
♪ You would say
We had nothing to do at all ♪
♪ We are resting
And saving ourselves to be right ♪
♪ For the Jellicle moon
And the Jellicle Ball! ♪
♪ Jellicle cats come out tonight! ♪
♪ Jellicle cats, come one, come all! ♪
♪ The Jellicle moon is shining bright ♪
♪ Jellicles come to the Jellicle Ball! ♪
♪ Jellicle cats come out tonight ♪
♪ Jellicle cats, come one, come all ♪
♪ The Jellicle moon is shining bright ♪
♪ Jellicles come to the Jellicle Ball ♪
[gasps]
[rhythmic breathing]
[all purring]
[lively music]
[rhythmic breathing]
[gasping]
[lively music]
[lively music continues]
[light music]
[upbeat music]
It's party time!
With your permission, of course.
[upbeat music]
[hissing]
[both snarling]
[upbeat music]
[gasps]
[rhythmic breathing]
[distant howling]
[all panting]
[somber music]
[pants]
♪ Silence ♪
♪ Not a sound from the pavement ♪
♪ Has the moon lost her memory? ♪
♪ She is smiling alone ♪
♪ In the lamplight ♪
♪ The withered leaves collect at my feet ♪
♪ And the wind ♪
♪ Begins to moan ♪
♪ Every street lamp seems to beat ♪
♪ A fatalistic warning ♪
♪ Someone mutters ♪
♪ And the street lamp gutters ♪
♪ And soon it will ♪
♪ Be morning ♪
♪ Memory ♪
♪ All alone in the moonlight ♪
♪ I can smile at the old days ♪
♪ I was beautiful then ♪
♪ I remember the time ♪
♪ I knew what happiness was ♪
♪ Let the memory ♪
♪ Live... ♪
♪ Again ♪
[tense music]
♪ Follow me home ♪
♪ If you dare to ♪
♪ I wouldn't know ♪
♪ Where to lead you ♪
♪ Should I take chances ♪
♪ When no one took chances on me? ♪
♪ So I watch from the dark ♪
♪ Wait for my life to start ♪
♪ With no beauty in my memory ♪
♪ All that I wanted ♪
♪ Was to be wanted ♪
♪ Too young to wander London streets
Alone and haunted ♪
♪ Born into nothing ♪
♪ At least you have something ♪
♪ Something to cling to ♪
♪ Visions of dazzling rooms ♪
♪ I'll never get let into ♪
♪ And the memories were lost long ago ♪
♪ But at least you have beautiful ghosts ♪
♪ And so maybe my home ♪
♪ Isn't what I had known ♪
♪ What I thought it would be ♪
♪ But I feel so alive
With these phantoms of night ♪
♪ And I know that this life isn't safe ♪
♪ But it's wild and it's free ♪
♪ All that I wanted ♪
♪ Was to be wanted ♪
♪ I'll never wander London streets
Alone and haunted ♪
♪ Born into nothing ♪
♪ With them I have something ♪
♪ Something to cling to ♪
♪ I never knew I'd love this world
They let me into ♪
♪ And the memories were lost long ago ♪
♪ So I'll dance
With these beautiful ghosts ♪
♪ The memories were lost long ago ♪
♪ So I'll dance with these beautiful ♪
♪ Ghosts ♪
♪ The moments of happiness ♪
♪ We had the experience
But missed the meaning ♪
♪ And approach to the meaning
Restores the experience ♪
♪ In a different form ♪
♪ Beyond any meaning
We can assign to happiness ♪
♪ The past experience revived
In the meaning ♪
♪ Is not the experience of one life only ♪
♪ But of many generations ♪
♪ Not forgetting something ♪
♪ That is probably quite ineffable ♪
[Old Deuteronomy]
Are you all right, my dear?
We haven't met before, have we?
No. I'm not from round here.
I was abandoned.
Oh, poor thing.
Would you like to see me
make the Jellicle choice?
-Am I allowed?
-Why wouldn't you be allowed?
I'm not a Jellicle.
Not yet, perhaps.
Come, we're about to begin.
[slurping]
Gus.
Gus, it's your call.
[exhales heavily]
I just wanted to wish you jolly good luck.
I'm a tremendous fan of your work.
Hmm.
What's your name?
Mr. Mistoffelees.
I'm a magic cat, you see.
Oh.
Do you ever get nervous?
No, no. It's all practice,
practice, practice.
Then nothing can go wrong.
Touch wood.
I've never played The Egyptian before.
Gus the Theater Cat.
Cross paws.
Hmm.
♪ Gus is the cat at the theater door ♪
♪ My name As I ought to
Have told you before ♪
♪ Is really Asparagus ♪
♪ But that's such a fuss to pronounce ♪
♪ That they usually call me just Gus ♪
♪ My coat's very shabby
I'm thin as a rake ♪
♪ And I suffer from palsy
Which makes my paws shake ♪
♪ Yet I was, in my youth
Quite the smartest of cats ♪
♪ Though no longer
A terror to mice or to rats ♪
♪ For I'm not the cat
That I was in my prime ♪
♪ Though my name was quite famous
They say, in my time ♪
♪ And whenever I join my friends
At their club ♪
♪ Which takes place at the back
Of the neighboring pub ♪
♪ I love to regale them
If someone else pays ♪
♪ With anecdotes drawn
From my palmiest days ♪
♪ For I once was a star
Of the highest degree ♪
♪ I have acted with Irving ♪
[exhales deeply]
♪ I've acted with Tree ♪
♪ And I like to recall
My success on the halls ♪
♪ When the gallery
Once gave me seven catcalls ♪
♪ But my grandest creation
As I love to tell ♪
♪ Was Firefrorefiddle ♪
♪ The Fiend of the Fell ♪
[screeches]
[laughing]
Ah.
♪ Then if someone
Will give me a toothful of gin ♪
♪ I will tell how I once
Played a part in East Lynne ♪
♪ In a Shakespeare performance
I once walked on pat ♪
♪ When some actor
Suggested the need for a cat ♪
♪ And I say now, these kittens
They do not get trained ♪
♪ As we did in the days
When Victoria reigned ♪
♪ They do not get drilled
In a regular troupe ♪
♪ And they think it is smart
Just to jump through a hoop ♪
♪ And I say, as I scratch myself
With my claws ♪
♪ Well, the theater
Is certainly not what it was ♪
♪ These modern productions
Are all very well ♪
♪ But there's nothing to equal
From what I hear tell ♪
♪ That moment of mystery ♪
♪ When I made history ♪
♪ As Firefrorefiddle ♪
-♪ The Fiend of the Fell ♪
-[thunderclap]
[music stops]
[all meowing]
I could do it again, you know.
[panting]
[Macavity] Bravo! Bravo, Gus.
Could I trouble you for an autograph, sir?
[Macavity gasps]
To see Firefrorefiddle come alive tonight
was truly inspirational and scary.
Macavity!
[laughing]
[Old Deuteronomy]
The next contestant is...
Skimbleshanks the Railway Cat.
♪ Skimbleshanks the Railway Cat ♪
♪ The Cat of the Railway Train ♪
♪ There's a whisper down the line
At 11:39 ♪
♪ When the Night Mail's ready to depart ♪
♪ Saying, "Skimble, where is Skimble? ♪
♪ Has he gone to hunt the thimble? ♪
♪ We must find him
Or the train can't start" ♪
♪ All the guards and all the porters ♪
♪ And the stationmaster's daughters ♪
♪ Would be searching high and low ♪
♪ Saying, "Skimble, where is Skimble? ♪
♪ For unless he's very nimble ♪
♪ Then the Night Mail just can't go" ♪
♪ At 11:42 with the signal overdue ♪
♪ And the passengers
All frantic to a man ♪
♪ That's when I would appear ♪
♪ And I'd saunter to the rear ♪
♪ I'd been busy in the luggage van ♪
♪ Then he gives one flash
Of his glass-green eyes ♪
♪ And the signal goes "All clear!" ♪
♪ And we're off at last
For the northern part ♪
♪ Of the Northern Hemisphere ♪
[whistle blows]
[rhythmic tapping]
[tapping intensifies]
[loud music]
♪ Skimbleshanks the Railway Cat ♪
♪ Skimbleshanks, Skimbleshanks ♪
♪ The Cat of the Railway Train ♪
♪ You could say that by and large ♪
♪ It was me who was in charge ♪
♪ Of the Sleeping Car Express ♪
♪ From the driver and the guards
To the bagmen playing cards ♪
♪ I would supervise them all
More or less ♪
♪ I will watch you without winking ♪
♪ And I'll see what you are thinking ♪
♪ And it's certain
That I wouldn't approve ♪
♪ Of hilarity and riot
So the folk are very quiet ♪
♪ When Skimble is about and on the move ♪
♪ You can play no pranks
With Skimbleshanks ♪
♪ I'm a cat that cannot be ignored ♪
♪ So nothing goes wrong
On the Northern Mail ♪
♪ When Skimbleshanks is aboard ♪
♪ Oh, it's very pleasant
When you've found your little den ♪
♪ With your name written up on the door ♪
[Jellicles] Whoo-whoo!
♪ And the berth is very neat
With a newly folded sheet ♪
♪ And there's not a speck of dust
On the floor ♪
♪ Then the guard looks in politely ♪
♪ And will ask you very brightly
"Do you like your morning tea..." ♪
♪ "Weak or strong?" ♪
♪ But I was just behind him
And was ready to remind him ♪
♪ For Skimble
Won't let anything go wrong ♪
♪ When you creep into your cozy berths ♪
♪ And pull up the counterpane ♪
♪ You ought to reflect
That it's very nice ♪
♪ To know that you
Won't be bothered by mice ♪
Skimble! Aah!
♪ You can leave all that
To the Railway Cat ♪
♪ The Cat of the Railway Train ♪
Cats!
-♪ Skimbleshanks the Railway Cat ♪
-♪ Skimbleshanks ♪
♪ The Cat of the Railway Train ♪
♪ And he gives you a wave
Of his long brown tail ♪
♪ Which says, "I'll see you again" ♪
♪ You will meet without fail
On the Midnight Mail ♪
♪ The Cat of the Railway Train ♪
[yelps]
[Macavity laughing]
Macavity.
[funky music]
♪ Macavity's a mystery cat
He's called "the Hidden Paw" ♪
♪ For he's the master criminal
Who can defy the law ♪
♪ He's the bafflement of Scotland Yard
The Flying Squad's despair ♪
♪ For when they reach the scene of crime
Macavity's not there! ♪
[dust rattling]
♪ Macavity, Macavity
There's no one like Macavity ♪
♪ He's broken every human law
He breaks the law of gravity ♪
♪ His powers of levitation
Would make a fakir stare ♪
♪ But when they reach the scene of crime
Macavity's not there! ♪
[tinkles]
♪ Macavity's a ginger cat
He's very tall and thin ♪
♪ You would know him if you saw him
For his eyes are sunken in ♪
♪ His brow is deeply lined with thought
His head is highly domed ♪
♪ His coat is dusty from neglect
His whiskers are uncombed ♪
♪ He sways his head from side to side
With movements like a snake ♪
♪ And when you think he's half asleep
He's always wide awake! ♪
♪ Macavity, Macavity
There's no one like Macavity ♪
♪ For he's a fiend in feline shape
A monster of depravity ♪
♪ You may meet him in a bystreet
You may see him in the square ♪
♪ But when a crime's discovered
Then Macavity's not there! ♪
♪ He's outwardly respectable ♪
♪ I know he cheats at cards ♪
♪ And his footprints are not found ♪
♪ In any files of Scotland Yard's ♪
♪ And when the larder's looted
And the jewel case is rifled ♪
♪ Or when the milk is missing
Or another Peke's been stifled ♪
-♪ Or the greenhouse glass is broken ♪
-[glass shatters]
♪ And the trellis past repair ♪
♪ There's the wonder of the thing!
Macavity's not there! ♪
♪ Macavity, Macavity
There's no one like Macavity ♪
♪ There never was a cat
Of such deceitfulness and suavity ♪
♪ He always has an alibi
And one or two to spare ♪
♪ Whatever time the deed took place
Macavity wasn't there! ♪
♪ And they say that all the cats
Whose wicked deeds are widely known ♪
♪ I might mention Mungojerrie
Rumpleteazer, Griddlebone ♪
♪ Are nothing more than agents
For the cat who all the time ♪
♪ Just controls the operations ♪
[Macavity] The Napoleon of crime!
[laughing]
Mwah!
♪ Macavity, Macavity
There's no one like Macavity ♪
♪ He's a fiend in feline shape
A monster of depravity ♪
♪ You may meet him in a bystreet
You may see him in the square ♪
♪ But when a crime's discovered, then... ♪
♪ Macavity ♪
♪ Macavity! ♪
♪ When a crime's discovered, then... ♪
♪ Macavity's not there! ♪
[Macavity] Aha! Yes!
The time has come
to make the Jellicle choice.
Old Deuteronomy, if you would.
As I am the only contestant left.
And, quite obviously, the best.
And so...
Never.
[blows air]
I choose the cat that deserves a new life.
I judge a cat by its soul.
-He's got soul.
-I've got plenty of soul.
You're a cheat, Macavity.
[Macavity yells]
[all panting]
Oh!
[ominous music]
[snickering]
[grunting]
Deuteronomy...
-I am going to the Heaviside Layer.
-Ah!
I demand that you grant me another life.
You will never go to the Heaviside Layer.
Oh. We'll see about that.
Growltiger, make her walk the plank.
-[hisses]
-[gasps]
-[Macavity chuckles]
-Say it's me...
-[Old Deuteronomy] Oh!
...or you'll drown in that river.
[Old Deuteronomy]
You'll never be my Jellicle choice!
-[Macavity] This is your last chance.
-Oh! Never!
Where is Old Deuteronomy?
Where is she?
We don't know.
[hisses]
Where is she?
Look, it was only a bit of fun.
We didn't know he was gonna take Old Deut.
There must be something we can do.
[Cassandra] We can't just magic her back.
[Victoria] Yes, we can!
Yes, we can.
You're a magician.
-What?
-[Munkustrap] It's not a bad idea.
Might be worth a try.
Really, I can't.
You could try.
Good luck.
[breathing shakily]
You can do it.
Cross paws.
-Can we get a spotlight?
-Please, don't make me do this.
And a drumroll, please.
[drumroll]
♪ The greatest magicians
Have something to learn ♪
♪ From Mr. Mistoffelees' conjuring turn ♪
♪ And we all say ♪
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
♪ I'm quiet and small, I am black ♪
♪ From my ears to the tip of my tail ♪
♪ I can creep through the tiniest crack ♪
♪ I can walk on the narrowest rail ♪
♪ I can pick any card from a pack ♪
♪ I am equally cunning with dice ♪
♪ I am always deceiving you
Into believing ♪
♪ That you're only hunting for mice ♪
♪ I can play any trick with a cork ♪
♪ Or a spoon and a bit of fish paste ♪
♪ If you look for a knife or a fork ♪
♪ And you think it is merely misplaced ♪
♪ You have seen it one moment
And then it is gone ♪
♪ But you find it next week
Lying out on the lawn! ♪
♪ And we all say ♪
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
[grunts]
You can do this.
[chuckles]
♪ My manner is vague and aloof ♪
♪ You would think there was nobody shyer ♪
♪ But my voice has been heard
On the roof ♪
♪ When I was curled up by the fire ♪
♪ And I've sometimes been heard
By the fire ♪
♪ When I was about on the roof ♪
♪ At least they all heard
That somebody purred ♪
♪ Which is incontestable proof ♪
♪ Of my singular magical powers ♪
♪ And I've known the family to call ♪
♪ Me in from the garden for hours ♪
♪ When I was asleep in the hall ♪
♪ And not long ago this phenomenal cat ♪
♪ Produced seven kittens
Right out of a hat! ♪
[mouse] What? Mr. Mistoffelees? My hero!
-Oh.
-Don't go!
-Oh, no!
-I'm falling!
-♪ And they all say ♪
-Oh, gosh! Run!
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
[sucks teeth, grunts]
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
Please.
[grunts]
[whimpers]
[Victoria] ♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
♪ And we all say ♪
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
[grunts]
[Old Deuteronomy] ♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
♪ And we all say ♪
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
-♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
-♪ So clever ♪
-♪ As you ♪
-♪ As me ♪
♪ Oh! Well, I never ♪
♪ Was there ever a cat so clever ♪
♪ As magical Mr. Mistoffelees? ♪
Ladies and gentlemen, I give you
the marvelous, magical Mr. Mistoffelees!
[cheering, meowing]
[Macavity] She's tricked me.
I will get there.
I will get to the Heaviside Layer.
I will win! You'll all see!
-[Jennyanydots whimpers]
-[growls]
Come with me!
[Macavity] Meow!
[suspenseful music]
[grunting]
[hissing]
[yelling]
[groans]
[grunts, pants]
Don't mess with the crazy cat lady.
[shouting]
Oh!
[retches]
-[yowls]
-Firefrorefiddle!
[Jennyanydots] Gus!
[ominous music]
♪ The Fiend of the Fell! ♪
Meow!
[Jennyanydots] Oh, you fiend.
♪ Daylight ♪
♪ See the dew on a sunflower ♪
♪ And a rose that is fading ♪
♪ Roses wither away ♪
♪ Like the sunflower ♪
♪ I yearn to turn my face to the dawn ♪
♪ I am waiting ♪
♪ For the day ♪
[somber music]
[hisses]
Sing.
♪ Memory ♪
♪ Turn your face to the moonlight ♪
♪ Let your memory lead you ♪
♪ Open up, enter in ♪
♪ If you find there ♪
♪ The meaning of what happiness is ♪
♪ Then a new life ♪
♪ Will begin ♪
♪ Memory ♪
♪ All alone in the moonlight ♪
♪ I can smile at the old days ♪
♪ I was beautiful then ♪
♪ I remember the time ♪
♪ I knew what happiness was ♪
♪ Let the memory ♪
♪ Live again ♪
♪ Burnt-out ends of smoky days ♪
♪ The stale, cold smell of morning ♪
♪ The street lamp dies ♪
♪ Another night is over ♪
♪ Another day is dawning ♪
♪ Daylight ♪
♪ I must wait for the sunrise ♪
♪ I must think of a new life ♪
♪ And I mustn't give in ♪
♪ When the dawn comes tonight
Will be a memory too ♪
♪ And a new day ♪
♪ Will begin ♪
♪ Sunlight through the trees in summer ♪
♪ Endless masquerading ♪
♪ Like a flower as the dawn is breaking ♪
♪ The memory is fading ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ It's so easy to leave me ♪
♪ All alone with the memory ♪
♪ Of my days in the sun ♪
♪ If you touch me ♪
♪ You'll understand what happiness is ♪
[sobs]
♪ Look ♪
♪ A new day ♪
♪ Has begun ♪
[soft music]
You are the Jellicle choice.
Thank you.
♪ All that you wanted ♪
♪ Was to be wanted ♪
♪ Never to wander London streets
Alone and haunted ♪
[Old Deuteronomy]
♪ All your memories of pain ♪
♪ Let them go ♪
♪ And you'll dance
With these beautiful ghosts ♪
[uplifting music]
♪ Up, up, up, past the Russell Hotel ♪
♪ Up, up, up, up to the Heaviside Layer ♪
♪ Up, up, up, past the Jellicle moon ♪
♪ Up, up, up, up ♪
♪ To the Heaviside Layer ♪
[grunting]
[laughing]
Up, up, up!
Heaviside Layer, here I... Oop!
[grunting]
[whimpering]
[screams]
[groans]
Ineffable.
-[Jellicles cheering]
-Meow.
[grandiose music]
-[laughing]
-You're alive!
♪ The mystical divinity ♪
♪ Of unashamed felinity ♪
♪ Round the cathedral ♪
♪ Rang "Vivat" ♪
♪ Life to ♪
♪ The Everlasting ♪
♪ Cat! ♪
♪ You've heard of several kinds of cat ♪
♪ And my opinion now is that ♪
♪ You should need no interpreter ♪
♪ To understand our character ♪
♪ You've learned enough to take the view ♪
♪ That cats are very much like you ♪
♪ You've seen us both at work and games ♪
♪ And learned about our proper names ♪
♪ Our habits and our habitat ♪
♪ But how would you ad-dress a cat? ♪
♪ So first, your memory, I'll jog ♪
♪ And say a cat is not a dog ♪
♪ And say a cat is not ♪
♪ A dog ♪
♪ With cats, some say, one rule is true ♪
♪ Don't speak till you are spoken to ♪
♪ Myself, I do not hold with that ♪
♪ I say you should ad-dress a cat ♪
♪ But always bear in mind that he ♪
♪ Resents familiarity ♪
♪ You bow, and taking off your hat ♪
♪ Ad-dress him in this form ♪
♪ O Cat! ♪
♪ Before a cat will condescend ♪
♪ To treat you as a trusted friend ♪
♪ Some little token of esteem ♪
♪ Is needed, like a dish of cream ♪
♪ Or you might now and then supply ♪
♪ Some caviar, or Strasbourg pie ♪
♪ Some potted grouse, or salmon paste ♪
♪ He's sure to have his personal taste ♪
♪ And so in time, you reach your aim ♪
♪ And call him by his name ♪
♪ A cat's entitled to expect ♪
♪ These evidences of respect ♪
♪ So this is this, and that is that ♪
♪ And that's how you ad-dress ♪
♪ A cat ♪
[indistinct chatter]
I believe you truly are a Jellicle cat.
A dearliccle cat.
[calm music]
[chimes]
[upbeat music]
[dramatic music]
♪ Follow me home ♪
♪ If you dare to ♪
♪ I wouldn't know ♪
♪ Where to lead you ♪
♪ Should I take chances ♪
♪ When no one took chances on me? ♪
♪ So I watch from the dark ♪
♪ Wait for my life to start ♪
♪ With no beauty in my memory ♪
♪ All that I wanted ♪
♪ Was to be wanted ♪
♪ Too young to wander London streets
Alone and haunted ♪
♪ Born into nothing ♪
♪ At least you have something ♪
♪ Something to cling to ♪
♪ Visions of dazzling rooms ♪
♪ I'll never get let into ♪
♪ And the memories were lost long ago ♪
♪ But at least you have beautiful ghosts ♪
♪ Perilous night ♪
♪ Their voices calling ♪
♪ A flicker of light ♪
♪ Before the dawning ♪
♪ Out here the wild ones ♪
♪ Are taming the fear within me ♪
♪ Scared to call them my friends ♪
♪ And be broken again ♪
♪ Is this hope just a mystical dream? ♪
♪ All that I wanted ♪
♪ Was to be wanted ♪
♪ Too young to wander London streets
Alone and haunted ♪
♪ Born into nothing ♪
♪ At least you have something ♪
♪ Something to cling to ♪
♪ Visions of dazzling rooms ♪
♪ I'll never get let into ♪
♪ And the memories were lost long ago ♪
♪ But at least you have beautiful ghosts ♪
♪ And so maybe my home ♪
♪ Isn't what I had known ♪
♪ What I thought it would be ♪
♪ But I feel so alive
With these phantoms of night ♪
♪ And I know that this life isn't safe ♪
♪ But it's wild and it's free ♪
♪ All that I wanted ♪
♪ Was to be wanted ♪
♪ I'll never wander London streets
Alone and haunted ♪
♪ Born into nothing ♪
♪ With them I have something ♪
♪ Something to cling to ♪
♪ I never knew I'd love this world
They've let me into ♪
♪ And the memories were lost long ago ♪
♪ So I'll dance
With these beautiful ghosts ♪
♪ And the memories were lost long ago ♪
♪ So I'll dance with these beautiful ♪
♪ Ghosts ♪
[lively music]
[somber music]